# **David Arrowsmith**

linkedin email

## Introduction

I'm a Software Developer experienced in web development with JavaScript and related technologies.

I currently work as a Frontend Developer at Twentysix, a digital agency with a diverse portfolio of clients.

I help deliver CMS-driven projects such as websites, digital sales aids and training tools. Though my commercial experience is frontend-focussed I'm comfortable working across the stack.

I also work part-time at <u>Command Shift</u>, a software development bootcamp. I teach web development fundamentals, and frontend development with React.

### **Skills**

```
CSS Docker Express Figma Git Handlebars HTML Lighthouse JavaScript Jest Jira Mocha MongoDB Mongoose MySQL Node.JS React React Testing Library SASS Sequelize Styled Components Supertest TypeScript VS Code Vue WAVE Xd
```

## **Experience**

#### **Frontend Developer**

Twentysix | December 2021 - Present

Twentysix is a digital agency with a diverse portfolio of clients. I help deliver frontend solutions as part of a multidisciplinary team.

#### Responsibilities:

- Contribute to projects such as new website builds and redesigns. I act as the primary frontend developer for a current new build.
- Complete Business-as-Usual (BAU) work such as bugfixes, minor changes and new features.
- Work with a variety of frameworks such as React, Vue and Bootstrap. Learn new technologies as required.
- Implement designs and behaviors to specification, as defined in Jira tickets and XD/Figma templates.
- Follow accessibility best practices and raise accessibility concerns.
- Work with the Backend team to define interfaces between the frontend and CMS/APIs.
- Participate in refinements, estimations and planning meetings (internal and client-facing).
- · Assist colleagues with technical and other issues.
- Help onboard new starters.
- · Attend interviews for new developers.
- · Perform code reviews.
- Create documentation to facilitate project handover.
- Host team rituals such as stand-ups and retrospectives.

#### **Tutor (Software Development)**

Manchester Codes | January 2022 - Present

Manchester Codes is a software development school. I help deliver their Software Developer Fast Track course, which focusses on web development using JavaScript and related technologies.

## Responsibilities:

• Deliver lectures in the following modules:

**Core:** Development environment setup, Tooling, Git, HTML, CSS & Javascript **Frontend:** React, React Testing Library, React Router, Sass, User Authentication

- Create new lectures consisting of presentations, demonstrations and workshops
- Create demo repos for student experimentation
- Support students by answering technical questions, helping them solve problems, and providing advice on best practices and ways of working.
- Update content on the learning platform
- Participate in internal discussions about course content and the school's direction

#### **Foundation Software Developer**

Thinkmoney | July 2021 - December 2021

I joined Thinkmoney through their Foundation Developer programme, which combined practical development work with a three-month training programme.

## Responsibilities:

- Apply updates and bugfixes to the Thinkmoney mobile application.
- · Participate in refinements and estimations.
- Participate in group training workshops.
- Complete OutSystems training courses within allocated timeframes. OutSystems is a low-code platform for website and app development.

#### **Senior Research & Development Chemist**

Sherwin Williams P&MC | February 2018 - July 2021

Prior to my career as a software developer I worked as a research chemist. At Sherwin-Williams I developed novel functional coatings (paint) for use in heavy industries such as oil & gas refinement, shipping and infrastructure.

## **Education**

- Manchester Codes Software Development Fast-Track March - September 2021
- Chemistry MSc by Research
  University of Manchester | 2016 2017
- Chemistry BSc
  University of Liverpool | 2006 2010

# **This Project**

# **Dependencies**

• <u>Marked</u> Lightweight markdown compiler